Mahmoud Alaaeldin

Consulting | Enterprise Agility | Digital Transformation | Change Manager

BACKGROUND

A Consulting professional with a proven record of generating and building client relationships. Over **8 years** of a diversified experience working across **APAC** and delivering strategic projects for high-profile clients, developing opportunities, scaling project management, and designing solutions, specializing in business process improvement, SaaS, program/project management in waterfall, agile and hybrid environments. Prior experiences include working in a Project/Program delivery, Business analysis, Subject matter expertise and Leadership capacities, with focuses on **Process improvement**, **Digital transformation**, **Long-term strategic planning**, Organizational agility, Software implementations, Service Delivery and Operations Excellence.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Management Consultant, Capco (Hong Kong) – September 2022-Present

Delivering innovative solutions and leading business transformation initiatives for high profile clients across the financial services sector

- Developed and led a process excellence strategy for a Tier 1 bank
- Led the process excellence and agile delivery capability at a Tier 1 bank
- Implemented process controls across APAC Data usage teams reporting to the Head of Data APAC
- Coached and trained several teams on Agile & modern delivery practices
- Conducted critical business process optimization for a large bank, leveraging automation to streamline workflows and improve productivity

Team Lead - Senior Consultant, Appnovation Technologies (Hong Kong) – September 2019-September 2022

Leading the APAC Atlassian team to deliver business software solutions across a diverse list of clienteles including the HKJC, AXA, Swire and others

- Rapidly promoted from Senior Consultant to **Manager** within 4 months of joining
- Led the successful delivery of a Resource and Financial management solution resulting in retained business with 6 additional projects and \$1M USD in revenue
- Delivered strategic projects for key players in insurance, covering topics like
 Demand Management, Claims, Purchase orders and Billing
- Spearheaded a complete strategic overhaul of the Supply & Demand
 Management process for one of Hong Kong's largest conglomerates
- Revamped the entire IT driven Supply & Demand Management process for one of Hong Kong's largest conglomerates

mahmoudahmedalaa@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-alaaeldin +852 5593 5514 (Hong Kong)

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent

Arabic: Native

SKILLS

- Business analysis
- Business process improvement
- Change management
- Customer relationship management
- Requirements gathering & management
- Solutions consulting
- Problem solving
- Software development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- Agile project management
- Leadership
- Market research
- Stakeholder management
- Strategic planning

Technical Software Consultant, Ease Solutions Pte. Ltd. (Singapore) – August 2017-August 2019

- Streamlined and automated claims management for a major German insurer, improving overall operational efficiency
- Led on-site training for a large international **Law firm** at their Manila office
- Delivered strategic projects for major clients including a Singaporean government organization, a top publisher, and the largest power station in Singapore
- Provided Consultation and data migration planning for a large Singapore based airline
- Serviced a diverse list of clientele such as Allianz, Marsh, Singapore Wildlife and Reserve, Elsevier, GIC, Senoko Energy, White & Case, Great Eastern, DeBeers group and others

Application Support Engineer, ServiceRocket (Malaysia) – January 2016-May 2017

- Received training from the Jira Software, Service Desk, and Confluence teams to develop expertise in these tools
- Solved complex troubleshooting issues with Atlassian software,
 collaborating with plugin vendors, internal teams, and customers to provide effective solutions
- Identified and reported several bugs to the development team, ensuring that issues were addressed promptly and effectively
- Authored several official Atlassian knowledge Base articles documenting solutions and workarounds for customers and internal Support Engineers

EDUCATION

- 2020 (Ongoing): Hong Kong University (HKU Space), **Postgraduate Diploma in Business Management for Digital Transformation**
- 2017-2019: University College Dublin (UCD), **Master of Science M.Sc. in Information Technology**
- 2013-2016: University of the West of England (UWE) Bachelors (Honours) of Software Engineering, Taylor's University, Malaysia
- 2011: Canadian Diploma (CIMP Canadian International Matriculation Program, Sunway University, Malaysia

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- Atlassian
- Salesforce
- Microsoft
- Cloud computing
- Groovy Scripting
- Python programming
- SQL
- Linux command line
- Data migrations

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

- 2022: <u>Certified SAFe® 5</u>
 Agilist
- 2022: <u>Professional Scrum</u> Product Owner (PSPO1)
- 2021: Microsoft Certified:
 Azure Fundamentals
- 2021: <u>Professional Scrum</u> <u>Master 1 (PSM1)</u>
- 2020: Honourable Mention in the MVP Nominations 2020, within 6 months of joining Approvation
- 2019: <u>Advanced Jira</u>
 <u>Workflows Badge (ACB-AJW)</u>
- 2017: <u>Atlassian Certified</u>
 JIRA Administrator ACP-JA
- 2017: Atlassian Certified
 Professional in Agile
 Development with JIRA
 Software